Guide to the Yale Music Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Music Collection
1796-1959
RU 341
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.56
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of music and lyrics for songs about Yale.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 45 (YRG 45), Yale objects and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in two series and in subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
The Yale Music Collection is arranged into two series: Series I (boxes 1-2) contains oversize material; Series II (box 3) contains the smaller material; and subsequent accessions.
Music in universities and colleges; Students' songs; Yale University -- Songs and music; Yale University -- Students
- Yale Music, Series I
  - YALE COLLEGE QUICK STEP, Composed by P. A. Smith. New York, 1843. 2p. No words. With title page illustrated with engraving of Old Brick Row and statement: Composed and dedicated to Miss Olivia Day. 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - WALTZ: SYLVAN REVERIES, by Edward Geary. Dedicated to M. P. Brooks. 5p. No words., 1845 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - THE SEA BIRD'S SONG. A DUETT AND CHORUS. Poetry by John G. C. Brainard (Yale 1815). Music by James M. Hubbard. New Haven, 1846. 3p. and title page with statement: "As sung by the Beethoven Glee Club of Yale College…And most Cordially Dedicated to the Hon. Wm. W. Boardman of New Haven." Words begin: "On the deep is the mariners' danger, On the deep is the mariners' death, Who to fear of the tempest's a stranger, Sees the last bubble burst of his breath." (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 'TWAS OFF THE BLUE CANARIES, OR MY LAST CIGAR. Composed by J. M. Hubbard. New Haven, 1848. 5p. & title page with statement: A Song, Written by a Student of Harvard University, Composed and Dedicated to the Students of Yale College. Words begin: "Twas off the blue Canaries." 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - YALE POLKA, For the Piano Forte. Composed by P. A. Smith. No words. New York, New Haven, 1849. 2p. 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - STUDENT-SONGS, Edited by Richard Storrs Willis (Yale 1841). New York, 1855. Variant copies, some separately published, others are reprints from his journal THE MUSICAL WORLD. Contents: (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ALMA MATER O. An American Student-Song: As Sung at Yale College on Presentation Day. Arranged by Richard Storrs Willis. 4p. Words begin: "We're gathered now, my classmates, to join our parting song." 5 copies. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - CO-CA-CHE-LUNK. A Student Song as Sung at Yale College on Presentation Day. Arranged by Richard Storrs Willis. 4p. Words begin: "When we first came on this campus Freshmen we, as green as grass." 4 copies. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SHOOL: An American Student-Song; as sung at Yale College. 4p. Words begin: "I wish I was in Boston city, Where all the girls they are so pretty." (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - PRESENTATION POLKA. Music by George C. Dunham (Yale 1856). No words. Boston 1856. 4p. & title page with statement: As performed by "Tyrolea" of Yale College, Presentation Day of the Class of '56. 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ANNIE LISLE. Words and Music by H. S. Thompson. Boston, 1860. 3p. & title page annotated: "The Sophmore Society Phi Theta Psi (founded 1864). "Amici" was their song. The tune to which "Amici" is sung was "Annie Lisle." 2 copies., Words in Yale Song Book (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - DELTA KAPPA EPSILON GRAND MARCH. by Alfred H. Pease. No words. 4p., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - WOODEN SPOON LANCIERS. Arranged by J. M. Lander. No music. New York, 1865. 8p. & title page with color illustration and statement: "Respectfully dedicated to the Cochleaureati of '66 Yale College, as performed by Helmsmullers Band at the Wooden Spoon Promenade Concert, Music Hall, New Haven, June 19, 1865". 3 copies. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - SONG OF THE SPOON. Arranged by S. Spier (Yale 1866) from the German of Julius Otto. New York, 1865. 4p. with color illustration and statement: "Respectfully dedicated to the class of '66… As sung by the '66 Glee Club at the Wooden Spoon Exhibition, Music Hall, New Haven, June 20, 1865.", 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - IVY SONG. Words by James Brand of '66. Author of music not given. New York, 1866. 4p. & title, page with color illustration and statement: "Respectfully dedicated to the Beethoven Society of Yale. The Ivy Song and Serenade as sung by the '66 Glee Club." Words begin: "Symbol of our trust when sorrow darkens on our shadowy way." (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - WALTZ OF THE BILLOWS: SONG OF THE BOATMEN. Song and chorus arranged for Soprano and Tenor Solo, and Duett with Chorus. Words and Music by Wm. W. Moses. New Haven, 1870. 3p. & title: page with color illustration and statement: "To the Officers and Crews of the Yale Navy of Yale College." Words begin: "Man the beat, boys! pull away! O'er the billows we'll rove." (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SOUNDS OF MIRTH GALOP. Composed by Gaylord B. White. No words. New Haven, 1872. 7p. & title page with statement: Dedicated to the Class of 1875 Yale College. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SECOND REGIMENT C.N.G. MARCH. By D. W. Reeves. No words. New Haven, 1877. 4p. & title page with statement: To Col. S. R. Smith and Officers of the Second Reginment C.N.G. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SERENADE. Composed by Louis D. Tourtellot (Yale 1886 Sheff). Words by Shelley. Negative & positive photostats of original manuscript. 2p. Words begin: "I arise from dreams of Thee in the first sweet sleep of night." (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - A LITTLE KNOT OF BLUE. Words by Samuel Minturn Peck. Music by Walter A. Phillips. New York, 1887. 3p. & title page with statement: To the Yale College Students. Words begin: "She hath no gems of lustre bright to sparkle in her hair." Songbook has music by T. G. Shepard. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - LOOMIS' YALE UNIVERSITY YORK. Mazurka arranged by Louis Felsburg. No words. New Haven, 1888. 2p. & title page with illustration of Old Campus Elms and statement: As Danced at Loomis' Academy. 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - THE OLD PUMP ON THE GREEN. By Walter H. Blakeslee. New Haven, 1890. 3p. Words begin: "There's a spot that's loved by all, 'Neath the elms so grand and tall." (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - YALE SCHOTTISCHE for Piano. Composed by J. Edward Geary. No words. New York, 1893. 3p., with page of dancing instructions and title page with statement: Dedicated to the Yale University Football Association. 3 copies. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - YALE UNIVERSITY MARCH. Composed by Amos T. Harrington (Yale 1894). No words. New Haven. 1893. 6p. & title page with statement: To my Mother. Autographed: "To Yale with compliments of A. T. Harrington." (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - GOBLINS' FROLIC. Composed by Florence O'Neill. Arranged by Chas. M. Couch. Allegheny, PA., 1894. 4p. and title page with statement: Characteristic Dance as Played by the Yale Banjo & Mandolin Club and Sousa's concert Band (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - THE YALE MARCH. Music by W. O. Johnson. No words. Chelsea, Mass., 1894. 3p. & title page with statement: Dedicated to the Students of Yale College. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - THE YALE MARCH: TWO-STEP. By Charles L. Van Baar. No words. New York, 1894. 4p. & title page with illustration (blue & white) and statement: Respectfully Dedicated to John Philip Sousa, Yale Society Two-Step. 5 copies & fragment. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - THE YALE MARCH: TWO-STEP. By Charles L. Van Baar, Arranged by Louis Tocaben for Mandolin & Piano. New York, 1895. 6p. & title page. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - YALE TWO-STEP. Composed by Bessie M. Warner. No words. Chicago, 1895. 4p. & title page with black & white illustration of couple dancing (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - THE ALUMNI MARCH: TWO STEP., By Charles L. Van Baar. New York, 1896. 4p. & title page with statement: Companion to the Famous Yale Society Two-Step. 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "YALE '99" MARCH: TWO STEP. By David Stanley Smith (Yale 1900). No words. Chicago, 1896. 4p. & title page. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - YALE WALTZ: JUNIOR PROMENADE ECHOES. By C. H. R. Miller. No words. Springfield, Mass., 1896. 4p. & title page with illustration of prom scene. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - PHI DELTA PHI: MARCHING SONG. By W. C. Tichenor. Cincinnati, 1897. 2p. & title page. Words begin: "We are a band of brothers true." (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - NU DEUTERON: TWO STEP. By Henry O. Price (Yale 1900). No words. New York 1898. 3p. & title page with photograph of Price and Greek letters Phi Gamma Delta (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - JUST ONE SONG FOR DEAR OLD YALE. Words and Music by Annie Cauley. New Haven, 1900. 2p. & title page. Words begin: "When the days are bright and balmy, When there's music in the dale." (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - JOLLY GOOD YALE. Words and Music by Octavia Lester. New Haven, 1901. 3p. & title page. Words begin: "Sing we in praise of our great University, Famous old Yale! scholarly Yale!" (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - UNIVERSITY WALTZES. By Frances L. Kirchoff, New Haven, 1901. 3p. & title page. No words. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - YALE BI-CENTENNIAL MARCH. Music by Erma Dessauer Troostwyk. No words. New Haven, 1901. 2p. & title page illustrated with photograph of Phelps Hall & Gate. 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - YALE BOOLA! MARCH AND TWO STEP. By A.M. Hirsh (Yale 1901). Arranged by G. L. Atwater, Jr. No Words. New Haven, 1901. 4p. & illustrated title page. 4 copies. Also: song sheet with three sets of words to be sung to the BOOLA MARCH, illustrated with drawing of "Adelina, The Yale Boola Girl," (4 copies); and small poster reproducing title page and part of music. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Letter from M. Heminway Merriman (Yale 1901) concerning the composer of BOOLA., (1957) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Birth of the YALE BOOLA MARCH." Card explaining the origins of song; advertisement. Published by Chas. H. Loomis, New Haven., (undated) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - CALL TO PRAYER. 1p. and fragment, handwritten, with note: "Coppy Wylie, by right of discovery." Words begin: "EE-MALI MOO-YAH! Lo, a multitude exceeding great.", 1902 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - YALE BANNER. March and Two-Step. Music by Allan M. Hirsh (Yale 1901). Words by Edward L. Fox (Yale 1893 Sheff). New York, 1902. 4p. & illustrated title page with Yale Seal. Words begin: "Ancient blue whose banners flew above Yale's citadel centuries ago." (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1907 YALE TWO STEP. Composed by Joseph Banneker Adger (student in special organ course Yale University). New Haven, 1903. 4p., title page, & list of students with home and local addresses, 2p. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - POLLY! OR EYES OF OLD YALE BLUE. Words by Roberta F. Watterson, Music by David Smith (Yale 1900). New Haven, 1903, 3p. & illustrated title page. Chorus: "And while now I drink to Polly, All ye sons of Eli true, Come and drink ye to the lassies who have eyes of Old Yale Blue." (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - PRO YALENSI. Dedicated to the Class of 1906. By Walter Ruel Cowles (Yale 1906). No words. New Haven, 1903. 3p. & illustrated title page. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - SLEEPY SWEEPS. Characteristic March and Two-Step. By Seth D. Bingham, Jr. (Yale 1904). No words. New Haven, 1903. 4p. & illustrated title page. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - SONS OF ELI. March and Two Step. Dedicated to the Class of 1906. By Arthur Leonard Westcott (Yale 1906). New Haven, 1903. 3p. & illustrated title page. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - YALE MARCHING SONG. Words and Music by Jason Noble Pierce (Yale Divinity 1906). 3p. & illustrated title page with statement: Inscribed to the Football Team of 1903. Words begin: "Dear old Yale, 'round thy standard now we rally." (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - CAPTAIN SMOKE. YALE CADETS MARCH TWO STEP. By John S. Farrell, Arranged by Harry Heald. New Haven, 1904. 5p.& title page. No words (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - DOWN THE FIELD. March & Two Step. Words by C. W. O'Connor (1904L). Music by Stanleigh P. Friedman (Yale 1905). New Haven, 1904. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "March, march on down the field fighting for Eli." 3 copies. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "SHEFF" WALTZES. Respectfully Dedicated to the Students in the Sheffield Scientific School of Yale University. Composed by Joseph Banneker Adger (Student in Special Organ Course, Yale University). No words. New Haven, 1904. 5p. & title page. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - THE CAMPUS-WALTZ. Composed by Elsie St. Germain-Davis. New Haven, 1905. 3p. & illustrated title page with drawing of Connecticut Hall. Words begin: "Down on the Campus, where Eli's sons's meet, A fam'ly of learning which knows no defeat." (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - MARCH TO VICTORY. March and Two-Step. Words and music by Kent Shaffer (Yale 1907 Sheff) New Haven, 1905. 4p. & Illustrated title page. Words begin: "March on to vict'ry. Old Eli Yale must never yield." 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - RELY-ON-ELI. March and Two Step. Words by C. B. McCormick. Music by Anita McCormick Blaine. (Probably Chauncey McCormick, Yale 1907). New Haven, 1905. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "There's not a foe in all the world that can prevail, Against the mighty battle line of Eli Yale." 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - TOUCHDOWN. March and Two Step. Words by Paul H. Sears. Music by Washington Kyle Sheffield (Yale 1908). New Haven, 1905. 3p. & title page. Words begin: "As cheer meets cheer across the field." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - YALE MEMORIES. Intermezzo. By George B. Ogle (Yale 1906). New Haven, 1905. No words. 3p. & illustrated title page showing banjo and mandolin players. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - BIG CHIEF ELI: A YALE WAR SONG. Words & Music by Marshall M. Bartholomew (Yale 1907 Sheff). New Haven, 1906. 3p. & illustrated title page with drawing of students dressed as Indians chasing Harvard man and the Princeton tiger. Chorus: "Oh, we are a band of Elis and we come ten thousand strong." (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - HERE COMES OLD ELI'S TEAM. March and Two-Step. Words & Music by Francis Manierre (Yale 1907). New Haven, 1906. 3p. & title page. Words begin: "Here comes Old Eli's team trusty and tried and true." (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - SONS OF ELI. Words by Donald Lines Jacobus (Yale 1908). Music by George Chadwick Stock. New Haven, 1906. 3p. & illustrated title page with drawing of Yale men on the fence by J. H. Clark (Yale 1907). Words begin: "We gather here old Eli's Sons with loyal hearts and true." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - THROUGH THE LINE. March. Words & Music by E. Howard Alofsin (Yale 1909). New Haven, 1906. 4p. & title page. Words begin: "Through the line go the men in blue." (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - VICTORY. A Football Song by W. A. Perry (Yale 1907). New Haven, 1906. 3p. & title page. Words begin: "Every son of Eli join us here all together give a rousing cheer." 5 copies. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - WHOOP IT UP. March and Two Step. Words by H. G. Dodge. Music by Stanleigh P. Friedman (Yale 1905). New Haven, 1906. 4p. & title page. Words begin: "Fight fight for Yale, The sons of Eli are out for glory." 4 copies. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - YALE BLUE RIBBONS. Characteristic Two Step. By Leo Friedman. No words. New York, 1906. 4p. & illustrated title page with drawing of woman. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - THE YALE BULL-DOG. March and Two-Step. Words & Music by W. Kyle Sheffield (Yale 1908). Arranged by G. L. Atwater Jr. 3p. & illustrated title page with drawing of Yale Bulldog. Words begin: "Bulldog is howling ready to fight." New London, 1906. 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - THE OLD BOYS. Words and Music by C. H. Goodman (Yale 1867 Medicine). New York, 1907. 4p. & title page with statement: To the Class of '67 Yale, As Sung at the Annual Banquet of Yale Alumni Association of St. Louis, Dec 21, 1906. Words begin: "Full many years have ambled by, since we sat on the fence, and sang the songs of dear old Mother Yale." (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - YALE GRIT. March and Two-Step. Words & Music by Gus Knight (Yale 1910). Chicago, 1907. 3p. & illustrated title page of football player with Yale Bulldog. Words begin: "Then give a cheer boys for Eli's men." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - BRIGHT COLLEGE YEARS: DEAR OLD YALE. Words by H. S. Durand (Yale 1881). Music by Carl Wilhelm. Arranged by P. Hollis Riblet. New York, 1908. 3p. & illustrated title page with photograph of the Old Yale Corner. Words begin: "Bright college years with pleasure rife, The shortest gladdest years of life." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - MARCH ONWARD. March and Two-Step. Words & Music by Edward C. Roberts (Yale 1910). New Haven, 1908. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Well now just look at Harvard/Princeton, She's in an awful plight." (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - MOTHER OF MEN. Yale University Prize Song 1907. Words by Brian Hooker (Yale 1902). Music by Seth Bingham (Yale 1904). New Haven, 1908. 2p. & title page. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - WHILE YALE SHALL HOLD HER OWN. Words by Marie A. Beach-Clarke. Music by Grace Adelaide Conley. New Haven, 1908. 3p. & illustrated title page with photograph of boat race. Words begin: "Some say that chivalry is dead, that men are knights no more." (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - YALE FOREVER MARCH AND TWO-STEP, By John T. Roberts. Hartford, 1908. 5p. & title page. Words begin: "Oh, Sons of Eli we are here as in the days of yore." (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - CHEER FOR YALE. March and Two Step. Words by A. Arthur Halle. Music by Fred. Kinsley, Jr. New York, 1909, 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Let's give a long cheer for dear old Yale." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - COLORS AND CHEERS. March - Two step. Music by Seneca G. Lewis, words by H. S. Leonard ('86 S). New Haven, 1909. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Hail! Hail! to you, Yale." (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - FIGHTING FOR ELI. March and Two Step. Music by George N. Finkelstone (Yale 1911). Words by J. McCarthy. New Haven, 1909. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Fighting for Eli, fighting for Eli, We're here to win boys." (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - THE LOYAL BLUE. Music by Traver Briscoe (Yale '12), words by E. P. O'Brien (Yale '12). New Haven, 1909. 4p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Just see the Blue - Roll up the score." (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - MEN OF YALE. March & Two. Step. Words by J. Joseph MacCarthy. Music by Harry J. Barreuther, Jr. New Haven, 1909. 4p. & illustrated title page with drawing of woman. Words begin: "Give a rousing cheer for old Eli and her men so true." 3 copies. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - SCORE FOR YALE. March & Two Step. Words by Thomas J. Aubrey (Yale 1911). Music by Monroe F. Zunder. New Haven, 1909. 4p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Rip thru the crimson line and score for Y-A-L-E." 3 copies. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - TARIFF BILL: A 1910 SONG. Words and Music by George de Romberg and Lewis Elwell. New York, 1909. 4p. & illustrated title page with photograph of William Howard Taft. Words begin: "Now the tariff bill is settled and country isn't nettled, tho' we haven't got revision downward yet." Chorus: "Oh Bill Taft, you are a dandy, You're a hummer, you're the dandy." (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - YALE BLUE FOREVER. Words and Music by E. W. Kellogg. New Haven, 1910. 4p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "There's a little strip of bunting dearer far than silken banner." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - DOWN THE FIELD MARCH. Music by S. P. Friedman. Words by C. W. O'Connor. New York, 1911. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "March, march on down the field, fighting for Eli." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - THE FLAG OF BLUE. By Dorothy Whipple. 1911, no place. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "The flag of Blue in triumph waves, the field of battle o'er." (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - HAIL TO YALE. March and Two Step. Words by Cole Porter (Yale 1913). Music by Arthur Troostwyk. New Haven, 1911. 4p. & illustrated title page. words begin: "Cheer, cheer for Eli today, Alma Mater true." (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - HERE COMES THE TIGER. By Henry Rogers. New Haven, 1911. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words began: "Hear the tiger roaring from his jungle land." (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - THE HOOLA BOOLA GLIDE. Words by Ken Shields. Music by George Christie. New York, 1911. 3p. & illustrated title page with photographs of singers Lee White and George Perry. Words begin: "Back up in New Haven where the students dwell, they do a raggy movement that is something swell." (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - THE LONG CHEER FOR YALE. March. Words and Music by W. E. Schultz (Yale 1909 Master of Arts). New Haven, 1911. 4p. & title page. Words begin: "Long cheer for Yale, boys, for our band is fighting." (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - THE SPIRIT OF YALE. Music by Monroe F. Zunder. Words by Samuel J. Newman (Yale 1911). New Haven, 1911. 4p. & illustrated title page with drawing by C. H. Austin Ayers (Yale 1911 Art). Words begin: "Eli Yale, Eli Yale, Rush the ball right down the field." (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - OH! YOU BULL DOG FROM YALE. Words and Music by George N. Finkelstone (Yale 1911). New Haven, 1912. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Come on Eli get them at the start, Come on Eli tear them all apart." 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - PARABALOU. Words and Music by Douglas S. Moore (Yale 1915). 1912, no place. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "With a brek-ek-ek-ex-co-ex and a brek-ek-ek-ex-co-ex we will march on down the field for Yale." (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - THE TEAM TRIUMPHANT. March. Words and Music by W.E. Schultz (Yale 1909 Master of Arts) New Haven, 1912. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Hail ever to the team! Ye sons of Eli, Eli Yale." (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - GOOD-NIGHT HARVARD. Words and Music by Douglas S. Moore (Yale 1915). New Haven, 1913. 3p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Good-Night poor Harvard, Harvard Goodnight, We've got your number you're high as a kite." (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - TOUCH DOWN: THE BULL DOG CRY. Words by D. L. Jacobus (Yale 1908). Music by J. N. Sanford. New Haven, 1913. 3p. & title page. Words begin: "We're here today to win the victory, We'll raise the bull dog cry." (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - VICTORIOUS ELI. March-Song. Words and Music by Arthur Troostwyk. 1913, no place. 4p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Victory for Yale, Harvard's team will fight to no avail." 4 copies (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - EVEN-SONG FOR ELIHU. Words by Benjamin R. C. Low (Yale 1902). Music by Giovanni E. Conterno. 1914, no place. 2p. Words begin: "Light of leading, Elihu, As the daylight falters; Beacon blaze where deeper blue darks the crimson altars." (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - MARCH "BLUE." Arrangement of Yale songs by M. L. Lake. No words. New York, 1917. 4p. & illustrated title page with drawings of Yale scenes. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - GET THAT HARVARD MAN. Words and Music by Spencer Vanderbilt (Yale 1920). New Haven 1919. 3p. & illustrated title page with drawing of woman with bulldog. Words begin: "Get that, get that, get that Harvard man." (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - YALE. Song from THE ROSE OF CHINA, A romantic musical comedy by Guy Bolton. Lyrics by P. G. Wodehouse. Music by Armand Vecsey. New, York, 1919. 5p. & illustrated title page. Words begin: "Though from fair New Haven, I have had to part, have I forgot?" (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - LET'S GO OLD ELI. Words by Frederick T. Burrows (Yale 1920). Music by George C.T. Remington (Yale 1922). New Haven, 1920. 2p. & illustrated title page with photograph of the Yale University Band. Words begin: "Let's go Old Eli, Break through that line." (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 1-2-3 FOR ELI! Words and music by Harry H. Shilkret. New Haven, 1925. 3p. and illustrated title page. Words begin "1-2-3 For Eli! Hurrah for Yale!" (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - ZULU WAIL (YALE BLUES). Words by Irving Bibo. Music by Frank Skinner. New York, 1927. 3p., illustrated title page, & 1p. of dance instructions by Edgar Jackson. Words begin; "Hear the sound of the drum, the Zulumen come." Chorus: "Blue Zulu, just hear him wail." (Box 2, Folder 36)